Okay, so I told you an array could store
multiple things. So let's see how this
magic variable works. So just like any
other variable, you'll create it with
the keyword let
and then you'll give it a name. Um let's
say I'm storing a bunch of first names.
So we'll say first names. Um and then
I'll say equals. And now if we were just
to store a string, I would put it like
that. Um,
maybe if we were to store a number, I'd
do that. Um, but as you can see, you're
still going to use the equal sign. But
if you want an array, then you want to
have things separated by commas. So, I
would want Toa and then Bruce and then,
and you can already see my computer's
starting to get mad at me. Um, in order
for your computer to know that this is
one value that just is separated into
smaller values, you need to use the
square braces. So, you can find the
square braces above your enter or return
key and then slightly to the left um
above your return key. So, I'm going to
delete this and I'm going to put those.
So, that right there is the syntax for
creating an array. You create a
variable, you give it a name, and then
you assign it equal to these square
braces. Now, if I want to put multiple
values in there, I could. So, I could
put Toa, I could put Bruce, I could put
Tim, I could put Natasha, um,
and I could go on and on and on, and I
can put a whole bunch of values inside
of one array.
So, well, if I asked you how to get to
something in the array, I said, "How do
I get to TOA?" Just visually speaking,
you say, "Well, first go to the array.
Then once you're in the array, go to the
first position." So, if I asked you how
to get to Natasha, you'd probably say,
"Well, visually speaking, go to the
array, find the item in the last
position. That's Natasha." Well, that's
exactly how you tell a computer how to
do it. Um, if you want to access um,
Bruce, then you say go to the first
names array and then in one of the
positions and you use square braces to
tell it you're accessing a specific
position rather than the entire array.
So just that right there, first names
accesses the entire array. If I put
square braces, I'm accessing an
individual item in the array. Just to
demonstrate this, I'm going to
console.log log first names. And if I do
that and save it, let's go live.
Um, and then we open up our terminal
in the console. Um, we got an array here
and it has TA, Bruce, Tim, and Natasha.
So, you can see that we access the
entire array. Now if we want to access
just one item in the array, we have to
say go to the array using its name and
then we have to say go to a specific
item in the array. So go to first names
and then go to computer start counting
at zero. So if we want Bruce then we
have to put one. So this would be
position zero. This would be position
one. This would be position two and this
would be position three. So we're saying
go to the array go to position one which
is two in. Now, if we save that and we
reload this page down here, we can see
that it says Bruce. And so, we've
successfully pulled an item directly out
of our array.
The same can be true for updating the
array. Let's say we want to change um
Bruce to be Natalie. I don't know why I
picked that one. I don't know how to
spell Natalie. Um but we'll try. So,
we're saying go to the first names Ray.
Go to the first position and set it
equal to Natalie. I think that's how you
spell it. And then once you've done
that, print out the name. And after
that, I'm actually going to print out
the entire first names list. So, I'm
going to save it. I'm going to come over
here and I printed out Natalie. And now
you can see that my array is to Natalie,
Tim, and Natasha. Um, where it used to
be to Bruce, Tim, and Natasha, we were
able to go into this position and edit
it. So now we have one variable that's
storing multiple pieces of information.
And then it makes it a lot easier to
track throughout our code because now I
just if I'm looking for any of the first
names in my code, I know they're all in
one variable and then I just have to
know what order they're in and then I
can edit them.
And that is the power of arrays. In the
next video, I'm going to show you how
you can add to an array and how you can
remove from an array. Thanks for
watching.